Marcel Thiemann

DIGITAL PRODUCT LEAD | MBA CANDIDATE | CSPO®

www.linkedin.com/in/marcelthiemann | www.github.com/cestmarcel | www.marcelthiemann.com

SUMMARY

Digital Product Lead who is helping Fortune 500 companies create delightful digital experiences delivered by state-of-the-art technical platforms. 7+ years of experience building engaging digital products for a variety of audiences with an international background in strategic communication and web development.

SKILLSET

Professional Skills Agile, Design thinking, Product management, Data analytics, Market research **Programming Languages & Engineering Skills** JavaScript, MERN-stack, SQL/NoSQL, HTML/CSS **Technologies** Digital reality, Connectivity platforms, APIs, IoT, Enterprise business technology

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Digital Product Lead10/2020-ongoingASTOUND GroupToronto, ON, Canada

- Leading and managing cross-functional product teams in the development of technical applications
- At the intersection of product development, development management, and technical project management,
 leveraging Design Thinking and Agile Methodologies to create delightful virtual experiences

Product Engagement Lead10/2017-02/2020Xapix, Inc.San Francisco, CA, USA

- Led go-to-market and product launch for an enterprise software product in the mobility space
- Cross-functional position: Product development, product marketing, and business strategy responsibilities

Digital Strategist09/2013-08/2015Glanzer + PartnerStuttgart, Germany

- Key team member in the company's digital unit. Focused on new business efforts and C-level presentations.
 - Planned integrated digital strategies for products and services in the automotive and technology sectors

EDUCATION

Quantic School of Business & Technology 03/2021-ongoing

Master of Business Administration 03/2021-ongoing

Washington, DC, USA

Expected graduation: March 2022

Berlin University of the Arts 10/2015–09/2017

Communication in Social and Economic Contexts, Master of Arts Berlin, Germany

Concentration: Design thinking, technology marketing, political communication

University of Hohenheim 10/2010–09/2013

Communications, Bachelor of Science Stuttgart, Germany

Concentration: Political communication, quantitative research, statistics

CERTIFICATIONS

Scrum Alliance valid through 03/2023

Certified Scrum Product Owner Credential ID 1345110

University of Toronto 05/2020-08/2020

Full Stack Coding, Certificate Toronto, ON, Canada